美國海軍於1969年3月3日
為頂尖飛行員成立菁英學校
目的是教導失傳的空戰技巧
並確保這少數的男女學員在畢業後
成為世上最頂尖的戰機飛行員
成績斐然
海軍稱之為戰鬥機武器學校
飛行員則稱之為
《捍衛戰士 ：獨行俠》
♪ Revvin' up your engine listen to her howlin' roar ♪
♪ metal under tension beggin' you to touch and go ♪
♪ highway to the danger zone ♪
♪ ride into the danger zone ♪
♪ headin' into twilight ♪
♪ spreadin' out her wings tonight ♪
♪ she got you jumpin' off the deck ♪
♪ shovin' into overdrive ♪
♪ highway to the danger zone ♪
♪ i'll take you right into the danger zone ♪
Today, we're looking at some of the hottest weather…
（加州莫哈維沙漠）
（9馬赫）
（彼得“獨行俠”米契爾上校 試飛員）
（管制區）
嘿
Hey.
怎麼回事？
What is it?
怎麼了？
What?
我們奉命禁飛，計畫被取消
We've been ordered to stand down.
They're scrapping the program.
他們說我們沒達標
They say we fell short.
合約門檻是10馬赫
The contract threshold is Mach 10.
那是兩個月後的門檻，今天是9馬赫
Mach 10 is supposed to be in two months.
Today's test point is Mach 9.
這不夠好
Well, that's not good enough.
誰說的？
Says who?
坎恩少將
Admiral Cain.
無人機騎兵
The Drone Ranger.
他要為無人機計畫挪用我們的預算
He wants our budget for his unmanned program.
現在正趕來親自終止今天的試飛
He's on his way to kill the test and shut us down personally.
他還沒到
Well, he isn't here yet.
他們要10馬赫
They want Mach 10,
就給他們10馬赫
let's give 'em Mach 10.
（獨行俠）
記住，合約門檻是10馬赫
Now remember, the contract threshold is Mach 10.
不是10.1或10.2，是10馬赫
Not 10.1. Not 10.2. Mach 10.
這樣計畫就可以繼續下去
That should keep the program alive.
我不喜歡你這個表情
I don't like that look, Mav.
我只有這一號表情
It's the only one I got.
這是暗星，收到嗎？
Control, this is Darkstar. How do you read?
這是控制中心，收到了，你呢？
Darkstar, Control. Loud and clear. How me?
收到，完成飛前檢查
Loud and clear. Takeoff precheck's complete.
啟動輔助動力
Ready for APU start.
啟動左引擎
Ready left engine start.
啟動右引擎
Ready right engine start.
滑行準備
Thumbs for taxi.
開始滑行
We are ready for taxi.
塔台，這是暗星，我正準備滑行
Tower, this is Darkstar. We are taxiing with information Alpha.
暗星，可以滑行
Darkstar, you are clear to taxi.
21跑道，風向210，風速10節
Runway 21. Winds 210, 10.
-油溫正常
-同意
-Fuel temps are looking good.
-Control concurs.
電池量95%，艙壓正常
Battery's holding at 95%. Cabin pressure looks good.
同意
Control concurs.
這是暗星，準備起飛
Tower, this is Darkstar. We're ready for takeoff.
要求爬升至600呎以上
Requesting an unrestricted climb to 600 and above.
暗星，儘管起飛吧
Darkstar, the runway and skies are yours.
切斯特坎恩少將
Rear Admiral Chester Cain.
獨行俠，坎恩到了大門
Maverick, Cain just pulled up to the gate.
喊卡還來得及
It's not too late to stop, buddy.
你知道這麼做的後果
You know what happens to you if you go through with this.
我知道不這麼做大家都會失業
I know what happens to everyone else if I don't.
暗星準備起飛
Darkstar is ready for takeoff.
大夥兒
Everyone,
準備起飛，先從引擎開始
go for takeoff, starting with engine.
-引擎，行
-熱源影像系統，行
-Engine, go.
-Thermals, go.
-燃油，行
-電力系統，行
-Fuel, go.
-Electric, go.
控制面，行
Control surfaces, go.
暗星，你可以起飛
Darkstar, Control. You're cleared for takeoff.
好吧，寶貝
All right, sweetheart,
最後一次飛行
one last ride.
爬升至600呎後，加速到3.5馬赫
Darkstar, you are cleared above 600. Increase to Mach 3.5.
Cleared above 600. Increase to Mach 3.5.
少將
Admiral.
-來得剛好
-我提早了，你也是
-Just in time, sir.
-I'm early. So are you.
可以解釋嗎？
You care to explain?
切換到超音速燃燒衝壓引擎
Transitioning to scramjet.
坎恩少將要求…
Mav, Admiral Cain is asking--
-命令
-命令你立刻降落
-Ordering.
-Ordering that we bring her down.
爬升至六…
…within six…
通訊不穩定，長官
This is where we've had trouble with comms, sir.
因為地球曲面差，這叫地球隆起
It's the Earth's curvature. It's called "Earth Bulge."
有人替你倒咖啡嗎？
Did anyone offer you a coffee?
Okay.
達到7馬赫，逼近8馬赫
He's at Mach 7, pushing 8.
-飛行數據？
-數據沒問題
-Flight data?
-Receiving. Data is good.
油溫升高，引擎仍然穩定
Temperature's climbing. Response is still stable.
感覺很好
We're feeling good.
8.8馬赫
Mach 8.8.
8.9
9馬赫
Mach 9.
他是世上最快的人
He's the fastest man alive.
呆頭鵝，看到了嗎？
Talk to me, Goose.
9.1馬赫
Mach 9.1.
9.2
9.3馬赫
Mach 9.3.
9.4
接近超高音速
Approaching high hypersonic.
風擋過熱警示
Windshield hot caution.
機身溫度升高
Surface temp rising.
快啊，寶貝，再快一點
Come on, sweetheart, just a little more.
只差一點了
Just a little.
快啊！
Come on!
10馬赫！
Mach 10!
把它放回你的國防預算中！
Put that in your Pentagon budget!
長官
Sir.
噢，不要
Don't do it. Don't do it.
只要…
Just…
再加一把勁
a little push.
慘了
Holy shit.
作為飛官你很帶種
You got some balls, stick jockey.
我不得不承認
I'll give you that.
噢，慘了
Oh, shit.
獨行俠
Maverick.
獨行俠！
Maverick!
謝謝
Thank you.
我在哪裡？
Where am I?
地球
Earth.
獨行俠
Maverick.
三十多年的軍旅生涯
Thirty-plus years of service.
戰功勳章
Combat medals.
獎項無數
Citations.
四十年來唯一擊落三架敵機的人
Only man to shoot down three enemy planes in the last 40 years.
傑出服役勳章
"Distinguished."
傑出服役勳章、傑出服役勳章
"Distinguished." "Distinguished."
但你卻升不了官，也不肯退役
Yet you can't get a promotion, you won't retire,
盡管多次出生入死，卻又死不了
and despite your best efforts, you refuse to die.
早就該成為二星少將，或是參議員
You should be at least a two-star admiral
by now, if not a senator.
但你仍留在這裡
Yet here you are:
上校
Captain.
為什麼？
Why is that?
人生就是如此難解，長官
It's one of life's mysteries, sir.
這不是笑話，我在問你問題
This isn't a joke. I asked you a question.
這是我的歸屬，長官
I'm where I belong, sir.
海軍不這麼認為
Well, the navy doesn't see it that way.
不再是如此
Not anymore.
你試飛的戰機
These planes you've been testing,
上校
Captain,
遲早有一天不再需要飛行員
one day, sooner than later, they won't need pilots at all.
需要吃喝拉撒睡的飛行員
Pilots that need to sleep, eat, take a piss.
違反命令的飛行員
Pilots that disobey orders.
你只是為其他人爭取一些時間
All you did was buy some time for those men out there.
未來近在咫尺
The future is coming,
而你不會參與其中
and you're not in it.
把他帶出基地
Escort this man off the base.
到他的寢室，看著他打包
Take him to his quarters.
Wait with him while he packs his gear.
一小時內出發前往北島航空站
I want him on the road to North Island within the hour.
北島航空站？
North Island, sir?
有一通電話來得時機剛剛好
Call came in with impeccable timing,
就在我準備罰你永遠禁飛之前
right as I was driving here
to ground your ass once and for all.
我很不想說，但是…
It galls me to say it, but…
只有老天爺和你的守護天使知道原因
for reasons known only to the Almighty
你又被召回捍衛戰士學校
you've been called back to TOPGUN.
-長官？
-解散，上校
-Sir?
-You are dismissed, Captain.
結局是無可避免的，獨行俠
The end is inevitable, Maverick.
你這種飛官總有一天會被淘汰
Your kind is headed for extinction.
也許吧，長官
Maybe so, sir.
但不是今天
But not today.
（加州聖地牙哥，美國戰機城）
（太平洋艦隊 美軍海軍航空隊）
（湯姆“冰人”卡贊斯基
美國太平洋艦隊司令）
彼得“獨行俠”米契爾上校
Captain Pete "Maverick" Mitchell.
你的聲名遠播
Your reputation precedes you.
謝謝你，長官
Thank you, sir.
那不是讚美
Wasn't a compliment.
我是博爾辛普森中將
I'm Admiral Beau Simpson.
航管指揮官，你認識貝茲少將
I'm the Air Boss. I believe you know Admiral Bates.
術士，長官
Warlock, sir.
我沒想到會受邀回來
Must admit, I wasn't expecting an invitation back.
這叫做命令，獨行俠
They're called orders, Maverick.
你們倆有個共通點
You two have something in common.
旋風是1988屆的第一名
Cyclone here was first in his class back in '88.
其實我只是第二名
Actually, sir, I finished second.
別對我期望太高
Just want to manage expectations.
目標…
The target…
是一座違反多方北約協定
is an unsanctioned uranium enrichment plant
未經批准的鈾濃縮工廠
built in violation of a multilateral NATO treaty.
製造的鈾對該地區的盟國
The uranium produced there represents a direct threat
造成直接威脅
to our allies in the region.
國防部要求我們召集攻擊小隊
The Pentagon has tasked us with assembling
a strike team and taking it out
在工廠運作前摧毀它
before it becomes fully operational.
工廠建在位於這座峽谷盡頭的地下碉堡
The plant sits in an underground bunker
at the end of this valley.
那座峽谷無法以GPS定位
Said valley is GPS-jammed
也受到多座地對空飛彈砲台防衛
and defended by an extensive surface-to-air missile array
加上數架第五代戰鬥機
serving a limited number of fifth-generation fighters,
以及多架儲備戰機保衛領空
which in turn are backed up by
a plentiful reserve of surplus aircraft.
包括幾架老舊的F-14戰機
Even a few old F-14s.
不是只有我們保留了老古董
Seems like we're not the only ones holding on to old relics.
上校，你有什麼想法？
What's your read, Captain?
通常出動F-35匿蹤戰機就能搞定
Well, sir, normally this would be
a cakewalk for the F-35's stealth,
但無法以GPS定位就沒轍
but the GPS-jamming negates that.
地對空飛彈的存在只能用…
And a surface-to-air threat necessitates
a low-level laser-guided strike
F-18以低空雷射引導攻擊
tailor-made for the F-18.
我認為…
I figure,
最少要投擲兩枚精準炸彈
two precision bombs, minimum.
兩架一組，出動四架戰機
Makes it four aircraft flying in pairs.
飛離峽谷必須垂直爬升
That is one hell of a steep climb out of there,
暴露在地對空飛彈攻擊範圍內
exposing you to all the surface-to-air missiles.
就算成功爬升
You survive that,
回程也得一路和敵機交戰
it's a dogfight all the way home.
你擁有這一切的實戰經驗
All requirements for which you have real-world experience.
並不全在同一項任務中
Not in the same mission, sir.
不
No.
有人會無法活著回來
No, someone's not coming back from this.
到底可不可行？
Can it be done or not?
工廠幾時會開始運作？
How soon before the plant becomes operational?
三週後，也許更早
Three weeks. Maybe less.
我很久沒開F-18戰機，而且…
Well, it's been a while since I've flown an F-18, and…
我不確定能信任另外三名飛行員
I'm not sure who I'd trust to fly the other three.
但我會想出辦法
But I'll find a way to make it work.
你誤會了，上校
I think you misunderstand, Captain.
長官？
Sir?
我們不要你飛，而是要你當教官
We don't want you to fly it. We want you to teach it.
教官？
Teach, sir?
我們召回十二名捍衛小組畢業學員
We've recalled 12 TOPGUN graduates from their squadrons.
你要從中細選出六名飛行員
We want you to narrow that pool down to six.
讓他們執行任務
They'll fly the mission.
上校，有問題嗎？
Is there a problem, Captain?
你明知道有…長官
You know there is, sir.
是啊
Yeah.
布萊德利布雷德蕭，也就是公雞
Bradley Bradshaw, aka "Rooster."
你和他老爸曾是搭檔
I understand you used to fly with his old man.
他的呼號是什麼？
What was his call sign?
“呆頭鵝”，長官
"Goose," sir.
他的死是很不幸
Tragic what happened.
米契爾上校被裁定沒犯錯
Captain Mitchell was cleared of any wrongdoing.
呆頭鵝的死是意外
Goose's death was an accident.
你是這麼想嗎？
Is that how you see it, Captain?
呆頭鵝的兒子也是這麼想嗎？
Is that how Goose's son sees it?
恕我直言，長官，我不是教官
With all due respect, sir, I'm not a teacher.
你當過捍衛小組教官
You were a TOPGUN instructor before.
那是三十年前，只撐了兩個月
That was almost 30 years ago. I lasted two months.
我不屬於那裡
It's not where I belong.
我就老實跟你說吧
Then let me be perfectly blunt.
你不是我的首選，其實根本不在名單上
You were not my first choice.
In fact, you weren't even on the list.
舉薦你的人是卡贊斯基上將
You are here at the request of Admiral Kazansky.
我非常景仰冰人
Now, Iceman happens to be a man I deeply admire,
他認為你對海軍仍能有所貢獻
and he seems to think that you have
something left to offer the navy.
我想不出是什麼
What that is, I can't imagine.
你不必接下這工作
You don't have to take this job.
但恕我直言
But let me be clear:
這會是你最後一項任務
This will be your last post, Captain.
當學校的教官，不然就退出海軍
You fly for TOPGUN, or you don't fly for the navy ever again.
我賭20塊你不能正中紅心三次
Twenty bucks you can't get three in a row.
（冰人：“怎麼搞得這麼僵？”）
（那個孩子還沒能準備好執行這項任務）
（冰人：“沒有人能
所以才會把你找來”）
（你可以先警告我）
（冰人：“講了你還會來嗎？”）
真不敢相信
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
彼得
Pete.
潘妮？
Penny?
-妳在這裡幹嘛？
-我才要問你呢
-What are you doing here?
-I should ask you the same thing.
-說來話長
-我不信
-Well, that is a long story.
-I doubt that.
Yeah.
你這次又惹毛了誰？
Who'd you piss off this time?
另一位少將
Another admiral.
那就對了
Exactly.
-妳還在生我氣嗎？
-彼得
-Are you mad at me?
-Oh, Pete.
我沒辦法一直生你氣，那就是問題
I can never stay mad at you. That's the problem.
我得說…
I got to say,
我以為永遠不會在北島航空站碰到你
North Island is the one place
I thought for sure I'd never run into you.
-妳來了多久？
-三年前頂下這地方
-How long you been here?
-Bought this place about three years ago.
-三年前？
-是啊
-Three years?
-Yeah.
就在你惹毛另一位少將被派去沙漠之後
Not long after you got shipped off to the
desert for pissing off that other admiral.
那是三年前的事？
That was three years ago?
你一定惹上大麻煩
You must be in a lot of trouble.
否則不會自願回來這裡
No way you'd come back here willingly.
不過呢…
Well,
你會想辦法解決
you'll sort it out.
不，我想…
No, I think…
-這是最後一次
-少來了
-I think this is it.
-Come on, Pete.
我認識你以後你就一直這麼說
You've been saying that as long as I've known you.
你開F-18載我兜風被逮到也這麼說
You said it after they busted you for
taking me on a joyride in that F-18.
沒過多久你就被派去波士尼亞
Then the next thing I know, you're off to Bosnia.
然後去伊拉克，兩次都有去
Then Iraq. Both times.
你每次惹上麻煩…
You get yourself in trouble,
只要冰人打通電話你又能飛
Iceman makes a call, and you're back in the air.
潘妮，這次不同
Penny, this is different.
彼得，相信我
Pete, trust me,
也許現在看似不可能
as improbable as it seems right now,
但你一定會再坐上戰機出任務
somehow you'll be back in a fighter plane
with your tail on fire.
-潘妮…
-太遲了
-Too late.
什麼？
What?
你本來要問我幾點下班
You were about to ask me what time I get off.
別用那副表情看我
Don't give me that look.
我沒用什麼表情看妳，我發誓
I'm not giving you any look. I swear.
我們每次的結局都一樣，彼得
It always ends the same with us, Pete.
這次就別再來一次
Let's not start this time.
好吧
Okay.
很好
♪ Put on your red shoes and dance the blues... ♪
妳看起來挺好的
You look good.
多謝了，老兄
Much appreciated, pal.
發生什麼事？
What am I missing?
“冒犯女士、海軍，或把手機放吧台
"Disrespect a lady, the navy,
就得請一輪酒”
"…and you buy a round."
請每一個人？
For everyone?
這就是規矩，幸好時候還早
I'm afraid rules are rules. You're lucky it's early.
拜託！
Oh, come on!
看看誰來了？
What do we have here?
原來是鳳凰
If it ain't Phoenix!
我還以為我們全是菁英，郊狼
And here I thought we were special, Coyote.
沒想到連遜咖都被找來
Turns out the invite went to anyone.
大夥兒，這是捕手
Fellas, this here's Bagman.
-劊子手
-隨便你
-Hangman.
-Whatever.
他可是唯一一名海軍飛行員
You're looking at the only naval aviator on active duty
曾在空戰擊落敵機
with a confirmed air-to-air kill.
別說了
Stop.
不過對方開的是韓戰時期的古董戰機
Mind you, the other guy was in
a museum piece from the Korean War.
-冷戰
-不同的戰爭，同一個世紀
-Cold War.
-Different wars, same century.
不是這個世紀
Not this one.
妳朋友是誰？
Who are your friends?
-復仇者
-粉弟
-Payback.
-Fanboy.
-嘿，郊狼
-嘿
-Hey, Coyote.
-Hey.
-他是誰？
-誰是誰？
-Who's he?
-Who's who?
你幾時進來的？
When did you get in?
我一直都在這裡
I've been here the whole time.
-他開匿蹤戰機
-他能隱形
-The man's a stealth pilot.
-Literally.
我是武器系統操作官
Weapons systems officer, actually.
毫無幽默感
With no sense of humor.
他們叫你什麼？
What do they call you?
巴布
Bob.
你的呼號啦
No, your call sign.
巴布
Bob.
巴布佛洛伊德
Bob Floyd.
你就是我新的武器官？
You're my new backseater? From Lemoore?
看來是這樣，對啊
Looks like it. Yeah.
♪ Bang a gong, get it on ♪
打一場撞球
Nine-ball, Bob.
把球排好
Rack 'em.
好吧
Okay.
-親愛的潘妮
-是
-Penny, my dear.
-Yeah.
再來四杯啤酒，老頭子請客
I'll have four more on the old-timer.
♪ And i'm the only son of a gun ♪
布雷德蕭
Bradshaw!
是你嗎？
Is that you?
原來你回美國啦？
This is how I find out you're stateside?
對啊，我想給妳個驚喜
Yeah, I just thought I'd surprise you.
我也給你個驚喜
I guess I surprised you back.
-見到妳真好
-我也是
-It's good to see you.
-Good to see you too.
-來吧
-謝謝
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
謝啦，老爹
Much appreciated, Pops.
趁人少的時候幫我結帳吧
How about ringing me up before the evening rush?
布雷德蕭
Bradshaw.
沒想到你會來
As I live and breathe.
劊子手
Hangman.
你看起來…還不賴
You look… good.
我是很厲害，公雞
Well, I am good, Rooster.
我超厲害的
I'm very good.
老實說
In fact,
我厲害到沒人信
I am too good to be true.
所以…
So,
有人知道為什麼把我們找回來嗎？
anybody know what this special detachment is all about?
任務就是任務，我不問為什麼
No, mission's a mission. They don't confront me.
我只想知道，誰會是隊長？
What I want to know: Who's gonna be team leader?
又有哪幾個夠資格跟我出任務？
And which one of y'all has what it takes to follow me?
劊子手，跟你只會提早進棺材
Hangman, the only place you'll lead anyone is an early grave.
跟你只會…耗盡燃油
Well, anyone who follows you is just gonna run out of fuel.
你就像隻公雞，對吧？
But that's just you, ain't it, Rooster?
只會窩在駕駛艙
You're snug on that perch,
等著永遠都不會來的…
waiting for just the right moment…
大好機會
that never comes.
♪ Slow ride ♪
我超愛這首歌
I love this song!
♪ Slow ride ♪
♪ take it easy ♪
他一點都沒變
Well, he hasn't changed.
是啊，還是老樣子
Nope. Sure hasn't.
♪ Take it easy ♪
你們看
Check it out.
又來了一群
More patches.
哈佛、耶魯、奧馬哈，靠，那是費茲
That's Harvard, Yale, Omaha. Shit, that's Fritz.
這是什麼任務？
What the hell kind of mission is this?
我們不該問這問題
That's not the question we should be asking.
大家都是頂尖高手
Everyone here is the best there is.
誰能當我們的教官？
Who the hell are they gonna get to teach us?
信用卡刷不過
It's been declined.
妳在開玩笑
You're kidding.
大夥兒，來吧
Hey, guys. Come on.
我不如付…
How about…
那不夠
That won't cover it.
我明天帶錢過來
I'll come by tomorrow and bring you the cash.
規矩就是規矩，彼得
I'm afraid rules are rules, Pete.
丟出去…丟出去…
Overboard! Overboard!
真假？
Really?
丟出去…丟出去…
Overboard! Overboard!
見到你真好，彼得
Great to see you, Pete!
Overboard! Overboard!
多謝了，隨時再回來
♪ Thanks for the beers! Come back anytime!♪
♪你讓我意亂神迷，神魂顛倒♪
♪ You shake my nerves And you rattle my brain♪
♪太多的愛讓人精神錯亂♪
♪ Too much love drives a man insane♪
♪你害我理智斷線，欣喜若狂♪
♪ You broke my will, but what a thrill♪
♪愛就像一團大大的火球♪
♪ Goodness gracious, great balls of fire!♪
♪我嘲笑愛情，以為那很可笑♪
♪ I laughed at love 'Cause I thought it was funny♪
♪但你姍姍而來，打動我的心♪
♪ But you came along and you moved me, honey♪
♪令我領悟到，愛情的美好♪
♪ I changed my mind, this love is fine♪
♪愛就像是一團大大的火球♪
♪ Goodness gracious, great balls of fire!♪
♪吻我吧，寶貝♪
♪ Kiss me, baby♪
♪愛就像是一團大大的火球♪
♪ Goodness gracious, great balls of fire!♪
高度八千英呎…七千英呎
Altitude 8,000… 7,000…
呆頭鵝，我抓不到彈射手把
Goose, I can't reach the ejection handle.
彈射…彈射…
Eject, eject, eject!
呆頭鵝！不！
Goose! Oh, no!
他真的很愛跟你飛行，獨行俠
God, he loved flying with you, Maverick.
♪ Come on, baby you're driving me crazy ♪
♪ goodness gracious great balls of fire! ♪
立正！
Attention on deck!
早安
Morning.
歡迎參加特訓營
Welcome to your special training detachment.
坐下來
Be seated.
我是貝茲少將，航空作戰中心指揮官
I'm Admiral Bates, NAWDC commander.
你們都是捍衛小組畢業生
You're all TOPGUN graduates.
頂尖飛行員
The elite.
菁英中的菁英
The best of the best.
那是過去式
That was yesterday.
敵人全新的第五代戰機趕上我們
The enemy's new fifth-generation fighter
has leveled the playing field.
細節不多，但要知道
Details are few, but you can be sure
我們不再擁有科技的優勢
we no longer possess the technological advantage.
獲勝的關鍵
Success, now more than ever,
取決於駕駛艙內的男女飛行員
comes down to the man or woman in the box.
你們有一半會入選
Half of you will make the cut.
其中一個會是任務隊長
One of you will be named mission leader.
另一半則是儲備飛官
The other half will remain in reserve.
你們的教官是你們的學長
Your instructor is a TOPGUN graduate
他擁有你們必須掌握這次任務的
with real-world experience in every mission aspect
實戰經驗技巧
you will be expected to master.
他的豐功偉業是傳奇事蹟
His exploits are legendary.
而且是這項計畫有史以來
And he's considered to be one of the finest pilots
訓練出來最優秀的飛行員
this program has ever produced.
他能夠教導你們的
What he has to teach you
極可能會關乎你們的生死
may very well mean the difference between life and death.
容我介紹彼得米契爾上校
I give you Captain Pete Mitchell.
呼號是獨行俠
Call sign: "Maverick."
早安
Good morning.
F-18戰機訓練及標準操作程序
The F-18 NATOPS.
包含了你們應該知道的一切
It contains everything they want you
to know about your aircraft.
我猜你們都背得滾瓜爛熟
I'm assuming you know the book inside and out.
-沒錯
-一定要的
-Damn right.
-Damn straight.
你說得對
You got it.
敵人也都知道
So does your enemy.
他又來了
And we're off.
敵人不知道的…是你們的極限
But what the enemy doesn't know is your limits.
我打算找到它們
I intend to find them,
測試它們
test them,
逼你們超越極限
push beyond.
今天就先從…你們自以為知道的開始
Today we'll start with what you only think you know.
讓我看看你們的能耐
You show me what you're made of.
公雞
Rooster.
布雷德利
Bradley.
布雷德蕭中尉
Lieutenant Bradshaw!
是，長官
Yes, sir.
我們之間沒必要這樣
Let's not do it like this.
你會把我刷下來嗎？
You gonna wash me out?
那要看你，不是看我
That'll be up to you, not me.
我可以走了嗎？
Am I dismissed?
早安，飛行員，我是你們的上校
Good morning, aviators. This is your captain speaking.
歡迎參加基本飛行訓練
Welcome to basic fighter maneuvers.
今天要演練空中纏鬥
As briefed, today's exercise is dogfighting.
只用機關槍，不用飛彈
Guns only, no missiles.
限低不能低於五千呎
We do not go below the hard deck of 5,000 feet.
兩架戰機一組，將我擊落，否則…
Working as a team, you have to shoot me down, or else.
-否則怎樣？
-我會反擊
-Or else what, sir?
-Or else I shoot back.
只要擊落一架戰機，兩架都算輸
If I shoot either one of you down, you both lose.
這傢伙太臭屁了
This guy needs an ego check.
我們會讓他吃癟
We'll see to that.
-不如來賭一把
-你想賭什麼？
-What say we put some skin in the game?
-What do you have in mind?
先被擊落做兩百下伏地挺身
Whoever gets shot down first has to do 200 push-ups.
大夥兒，很多下耶
Guys. That's a lot of push-ups.
訓練不是叫假的，長官
They don't call it an exercise for nothing, sir.
那就一言為定
You got yourself a deal, gentlemen.
開戰了，拼了啦
Fight's on. Let's turn and burn.
粉弟，看到他嗎？
Fanboy, you see him?
他不在前方，一定在後面
Nothing on radar up ahead. He must be somewhere behind us.
-可惡
-搞什麼？
-Damn it!
-What the hell?
該死！
Shit!
♪ We Don't get fooled again ♪
別這麼衝，獨行俠
Easy, Maverick.
別在第一天就被炒魷魚
Let's try not to get fired on the first day.
看見目標…獨行俠逼近，向左急轉
Tally, tally, tally! Maverick's coming in! Break left!
向左急轉
Breaking left.
復仇者，你的僚機呢？
Payback, where's your wingman?
-公雞，你在哪？
-我會罩你
-Rooster, where are you?
-I got your back.
我來了，撐著點，撐著點
I'm coming. Hang in there. Hang in there.
快點，兄弟！快點
Hurry up, man! Hurry up!
-復仇者，向右急轉
-向右急轉
-Payback, break right.
-Breaking right.
公雞救了你們，但他會付出代價
Rooster just saved your life, fellas. But it's gonna cost him.
這次不會，老頭
Not this time, old man.
別被他激怒，獨行俠
Don't let him get to you, Maverick.
♪ Smile and grin at the change all around pick up my guitar... ♪
公雞，你飛得太低，快爬升 你快到限低了
Rooster, you're too low! Pull up! You're hitting the hard deck!
-高度，高度
-慘了
-Altitude. Altitude.
-Oh, shit.
♪ Get on my knees and pray ♪
你被擊落了
That's a kill.
伏低，109下
Down! 109.
伏低，110下
Down! 110.
那應該是我們
That should be us down there.
但並不是
But it's not.
現在你們也知道公雞會犧牲自己
And now you know a little something about Rooster.
留守在跑道，等我們回來
Hold that tarmac down till we get back, brother, all right?
拍一張，大夥兒
Get in there, boys.
-你被擊落了
-靠
-That's a kill.
-Damn!
-你死了
-可惡
-Smoked.
-Damn it.
剛才自拍得很爽嘛，伏低
It was all fun and games in that selfie, wasn't it? Down!
嘿，鳳凰
Say, Phoenix.
不如告訴大家“巴布”是別的小名
How's about we tell everybody "Bob" stands for something?
-不只是羅勃特
-別上當
-Other than Robert, I mean.
-Don't take the bait, Bob.
想知道他為什麼叫劊子手嗎？
Want to know why we call him Hangman?
我想到了，“巴布叭噗”
I got it. "Baby On Board."
靠！
Shit!
各位飛官好，開戰了
Greetings, aviators. Fight's on.
鳳凰，把這傢伙擊落
All right, Phoenix, let's take this guy out!
小心後方，鳳凰
Watch your back, Phoenix.
-向右急轉
-Break right!
-Breaking right.
他去哪兒？
Where's he going?
他是劊子手，只會害死你
That's why we call him Hangman.
He'll always hang you out to dry.
丟下你的僚機
Leaving your wingman.
很久沒看過這一招了
There's a strategy I haven't seen in a while.
他在笑妳，妳忍得了嗎？
He called you a man, Phoenix. You gonna take that?
只要他噹你就忍得了
So long as he doesn't call you a man.
巴布，獨行俠在哪？
Talk to me, Bob. Where's Maverick?
天啊，他已經繞回來了！
Jesus, his nose is already coming around!
幫我甩掉他，劊子手
Get him off me, Hangman!
各位聽眾，我要埋了這化石
For all you folks at home, this is how you bury a fossil.
劊子手，該教訓你了
All right, Hangman. Time to teach you a lesson.
-妳掛了，鳳凰
-混蛋
-You're out, Phoenix.
-Son of a bitch!
開戰了
That's it.
-來吧，獨行俠，看你有多厲害
-來追我啊
-Let's go, Mav. Let's see what you got.
-Come get me.
惡魔散退，劊子手來也
Evil be gone. Hangman's coming.
我得承認，你很行
Yeah, you're good. I'll give you that.
♪ Meet the new boss ♪
靠，看不到他，我離他多近？
Shit. Phoenix, I can't see him. How close am I?
-鳳凰？
-我掛了，豬頭
-Phoenix?
-I'm dead, dickhead.
下輩子再見，捕手
See you in the afterlife, Bagman.
他在哪？他在哪？
Where is he? Where is he?
你死了
That's a kill.
79，伏低，80，伏低
Seventy-nine. Down. Eighty. Down.
開戰吧，下一個是誰？
Let's go. Who's next?
-擊中你了，奧馬哈
-可惡
-I got you, Omaha.
-Damn it!
-你死了，郊狼
-收到
-Lights out, Coyote.
-Copy kill.
伏低，51，伏低，52
Down. Fifty-one. Down. Fifty-two.
公雞，能問個私人問題嗎？
So, Rooster, mind if I ask you a personal question?
我能說不能嗎？
Would it matter if I did?
你和獨行俠有什麼過節？
What's the story with you and Maverick?
-你好像跟他過不去
-不關你的事
-It seems like he's got you rattled.
-That's none of your business.
他到底在哪裡？
Now where the hell is he?
一直都在這裡
Been here the whole time.
哇哩咧
Holy shit.
看到我了嗎？
You see me now?
來吧，速戰速決
Come on, let's get it over with.
開戰了
Fight's on!
那兩個人到底是怎麼回事？
What is with these two?
你逼我們盤旋俯衝，要怎麼解套？
All right, you put us here. How you gonna get yourself out?
你隨時都能撤
You can bail out anytime.
公雞，你想俯衝到多低？
How low you want to go, Rooster?
比你更低，你懂我意思
I can go as low as you, sir! And that's saying something.
過去的就讓它過去
What's past is past. For both of us.
你很想，對吧？
You'd like to believe that, wouldn't you?
限低是五千呎，就快到了
Hard deck is 5,000 feet, fellas. You are running out of room.
高度
Altitude.
你打算害我們都墜機
Your strategy is about to run us into the ground.
-你想怎樣？
-高度…
-What's your move?
-Altitude. Altitude.
高度
Altitude.
高度…高度…
Altitude. Altitude. Altitude.
高度，高度
Altitude. Altitude.
爬升…爬升…
Pull up! Pull up! Pull up! Pull up!
Pull up! Pull up!
你行的，別猶豫，放手去做
You got it. Don't think, just do.
你逮到他了，飛低然後射擊
Come on, Rooster, you got him! Drop down and take the shot!
太低了
It's too low.
太遲了，你錯過機會
Too late. You had your chance.
你被擊落，玩完了
That's a kill. Knock it off.
可惡
Damn it!
還是老樣子
Same old Rooster.
去找宏多做伏地挺身
Go see Hondo about your push-ups.
好了，夠了
All right, that's enough.
公雞，夠了
Rooster. That's enough, man.
違紀抗命，你想被踢走嗎？
Breaking the hard deck, insubordination.
Are you trying to get kicked out?
別擔心
Don't worry about it.
我想要出這項任務
Look, I'm going on this mission.
但你被踢走，我就得和劊子手合作
But if you get kicked out, you leave us flying with Hangman.
-那是怎麼回事？
-他拿掉我的文件
-Talk to me. What the hell was that?
-He pulled my papers.
-什麼？誰？
-獨行俠
-What? Who?
-Maverick.
他拿掉我海軍官校的申請書
He pulled my application to the Naval Academy.
害我浪費了四年
Set me back four years.
他為什麼要這麼做？
Why would he do that?
限低是五千呎
The hard deck is 5,000 feet above ground level.
不只是為了飛行員的安全
A parameter is set not just for the safety of our pilots,
也是為了戰機的安全
but for the safety of their aircraft.
五千呎不只是規定，更是一條鐵律
5,000 feet is not just a rule.
It is a law, as immutable as gravity.
這項任務的限低會更低
The hard deck will be much lower for the mission, sir.
沒我的允許不准更改
And it will not change without my approval!
尤其是在演練空戰的時候
Especially not in the middle of an exercise.
你那招眼鏡蛇機動會害死你們三個
And that Cobra maneuver of yours?
That could've got all three of you killed.
我不想再看到那種屁事
I never want to see that shit again.
你以為你在教什麼？
What exactly do you suppose you were teaching, Captain?
他們雖然很優秀，但還有得要學
That as good as they are, sir,
they still have something to learn.
他們是世上最頂尖的飛行員
You are talking about the best
fighter pilots on the planet, Captain.
他們一直都被吹捧
And they've been told that their entire career,
卻只會從高空投擲炸彈
while they've been dropping bombs from a high altitude
沒有空戰的經驗
with little to no dogfighting.
這是他們從來沒有執行過的任務
The parameters of this mission call for
something they have never encountered.
你只有不到三週要教會他們團隊合作
Okay, you have less than three weeks
to teach them how to fight as a team
還有擊中目標
and how to strike the target.
也要活著回來
And how to come home.
必須活著回來，長官
And how to come home, sir.
每項任務都有風險
Every mission has its risks.
這些飛行員都能接受
These pilots accept that.
我不接受，長官
I don't, sir.
從今天起，每天早上
Every morning, from this day forward,
你要書面報告你的教戰計畫
you will brief us on your instructional plans in writing.
沒有我的允許不准做出更動
And nothing will change without my express approval.
-包括限低？
-尤其是限低，上校
-Including the hard deck, sir?
-Especially the hard deck, Captain.
長官
Sir.
這是什麼？
What is this?
要求降低限低，長官
It's a request to lower the hard deck, sir,
為了演練低空轟炸任務
to practice a low-level bombing run per the mission parameters.
有關時機的掌控要多注意點，上校
You could learn a thing or two about timing, Captain.
唷，郊狼
Yo, Coyote.
你看看
Take a look at this.
傳奇人物，就是他
The man, the legend. There he is.
不是啦，他旁邊那個
No, no, no. Next to him.
很眼熟吧？
He look familiar to you?
這什麼情況？
What have we here?
布雷德蕭
Bradshaw.
我不敢相信
As I live and breathe.
弟歐…你長大了
Hey, Theo, you got big.
嘿，獨行俠
Hey, Mav.
艾蜜莉雅？
Amelia?
我知道，我長大了
I know. I got big.
是啊
Yes.
酒吧五點才開
Bar opens at 5:00.
我只是來還錢的
No, I just came by to pay off a debt.
媽！
Mom!
-妳爸好嗎？
-跟他老婆在夏威夷
-Hey, how's your dad?
-With his wife, in Hawaii.
媽！
Mom!
獨行俠說他欠妳錢
Mav says he owes you money.
-沒關係啦
-我堅持
-Don't worry about it.
-I insist.
謝了，上校，酒帳還清了
Thank you, Captain. Consider your tab closed.
還是上校？
Captain? Still?
戰功彪炳的上校
A highly decorated captain.
做完功課
Finish up.
得把帆船開到船塢
We have to get the boat to the yard.
-我不行
-什麼意思？
-I can't go.
-What do you mean, you can't go?
明天要抽考，我得用功唸書
他們今天才通知我們
Test tomorrow. I have to study. They only told us today.
我不能一個人駕船
Well, I can't sail her alone.
用引擎啊
Just use the engine.
為什麼要開到船塢？
Why are we taking her to the yard?
修理引擎
To fix the engine.
我能幫忙
I can help.
-浪比我預期的更大
-還用說
-Little rougher than I was expecting.
-You don't say.
拉住控帆索，減低風力
Pull on the backstay. We'll de-power the sails.
好啊
Okay.
那什麼意思？
What does that mean?
你是海軍耶
You're supposed to be in the navy!
我不會航船，只會降落在航母
I don't sail boats, Penny. I land on them.
這就像打開襟翼一樣
It's sort of like raising the flaps on an airplane.
我要怎麼做？
So how do I do that?
拉住那條綠繩索
You pull on that green line up there.
綠繩索
Green line.
對，用力拉
Yep. Pull it hard.
很好，用力轉那個曲柄
Yep. Crank that winch right there,
拉緊三角帆
tighten the jib.
-用力轉，還行嗎？
-行
-Crank it. You okay?
-Yeah.
很好
Good.
現在…
Now,
準備好了嗎？
you ready?
準備好什麼？
For what?
拉起風帆
The afterburner.
現在你才算是海軍
Now you're in the navy.
今天謝謝你幫忙
Thanks for helping out today.
我好像沒幫到什麼
I'm not exactly sure I helped.
別那副表情
Don't give me that look.
什麼表情？
What look?
那副表情
That one.
晚安，彼得
Good night, Pete.
晚安，潘妮
Night, Penny.
媽，是妳嗎？
Mom, is that you?
對啊
Yeah, it's me.
我替妳做晚飯
I'll make you dinner.
Okay.
（抵達目標時間：三分鐘）
時間…是最大的敵人
Time is your greatest enemy.
任務第一階段是低空進入
Phase one of the mission will be a low-level ingress
兩架戰機一組進行攻擊
attacking in two-plane teams.
沿著狹窄的峽谷飛至目標
You'll fly along this narrow canyon to your target.
雷達導引地對空飛彈防衛該地區
Radar-guided surface-to-air missiles defend the area.
這些飛彈…極度致命
These SAMs, they're lethal.
但它們負責防禦領空，不是峽谷
But they were designed to protect
the skies above, not the canyon below.
因為敵人知道沒人會瘋狂到飛進峽谷
That's because the enemy knows no one is
insane enough to try and fly below them.
我就是要訓練你們這麼做
That's exactly what I'm gonna train you to do.
任務當天的飛行高度最多100呎
On the day, your altitude will be 100 feet maximum.
超過這高度就會被雷達偵測…
You exceed this altitude, radar will spot you,
你就死定了
and you're dead.
飛行速度是660節…
Your airspeed will be 660 knots
最低速度
minimum.
抵達目標時間是兩分半鐘
Time to target: two and a half minutes.
因為第五代戰機在附近軍用機場待命
That's because fifth-generation fighters
wait at an air base nearby.
F-18戰機對上它們…必死無疑
In a head-to-head with these planes in your F-18s, you're dead.
你們得飛進峽谷，擊中目標
That's why you need to get in, hit your target and be gone
趁那些戰機尚未抵達時飛離敵區
before these planes even have a chance of catching you.
時間就變得至關重要
This makes time your greatest adversary.
你們要照著模擬峽谷的航道飛行
You'll fly a route in your nav system
that simulates the canyon.
越快飛過峽谷
The faster you navigate this canyon,
越不會被敵軍雷達偵測
the harder it'll be to stay
under the radar of these enemy SAMs.
彎度越窄
The tighter the turns,
身體承受的G力就越大
the more intensely the force of gravity
on your body multiplies,
肺部受到擠壓
compressing your lungs,
血液離開大腦
forcing the blood from your brain,
減低判斷及反應時間
impairing your judgment and reaction time.
今天的訓練比較輕鬆
So for today's lesson, we're gonna take it easy on you.
高度三百呎，目標時間三分鐘
Max ceiling: 300 feet. Time to target: three minutes.
祝好運
Good luck.
目標時間一分半鐘
Time to target is one minute 30.
我們落後兩秒，加速到480節
We are two seconds behind. Increase to 480 knots.
我們得快點，郊狼
We got to move, Coyote.
收到，加速中
Copy. Increasing speed.
噢，靠
Oh, shit!
他們怎麼會死？
Why are they dead?
我們超過300呎
一枚地對空飛彈擊落我們
We broke the 300-foot ceiling, and a SAM took us out.
不對，他們怎麼會死？
No. Why are they dead?
我減速卻沒警告她，是我的錯
I slowed down and didn't give her
a warning. It was my fault.
你為什麼沒警告隊友？
Was there a reason you didn't communicate with your team?
我正在專心…
I was focusing on--
說出家屬在葬禮能接受的理由
One that their family will accept at the funeral.
我沒有，長官
None, sir.
妳熟知地形，怎麼不知道要急轉？
Why didn't you anticipate the turn?
You were briefed on the terrain.
別告訴我，告訴他的家屬
Don't tell me. Tell it to his family.
劊子手，慢點，峽谷越來越窄
Hangman, ease up. The canyon's getting tighter.
不行，復仇者，你要加速
Negative, Payback. Increase your speed.
-你飛得太快
-提早達標是好事
-You're going too fast, man.
-No harm in being ahead of schedule.
快減速，我無法留在航道
Damn it, slow down! I can't stay on the course!
你會撞上山壁，小心…
You're gonna hit the wall! Watch out! Watch out!
-怎麼回事？
-我飛到最快
-What happened?
-I flew as fast as I could.
像是火燒屁股一樣
Kind of like my ass depended on it.
你危及到隊友，僚機也掛了
And you put your team in danger, and your wingman's dead.
他們跟不上我
They couldn't keep up.
公雞，我們落後20秒
Rooster, we're 20 seconds behind and dropping.
沒問題，速度可以
We're fine. Speed is good.
加速到500節
Increase to 500 knots.
-不，耶魯，別加速
-我們落後了
-Negative, Yale. Hold your speed.
-Rooster, we're late!
我們還活著，直飛時再趕進度
We're alive. We'll make up time in the straightaway.
我們會來不及
We are not gonna make it.
相信我，保持速度，趕得到的
Just trust me. Maintain your speed. We can make it.
你為什麼會死？
Why are you dead?
你是隊長，隊友為什麼會死？
You're team leader up there.
Why are you, why is your team dead?
長官，只有他抵達目標
Sir, he's the only one who made it to the target.
遲了一分鐘
A minute late.
他給敵機時間擊落他
He gave enemy aircraft time to shoot him down.
-他死了
-你不能確定
-He is dead.
-You don't know that.
你飛得太慢，浪費了時間
You're not flying fast enough.
You don't have a second to waste.
我們成功抵達目標
We made it to the target.
更優越的敵機在返航時攔截你
And superior enemy aircraft intercepted you on your way out.
-那就展開空戰
-對上第五代戰機
-Then it's a dogfight.
-Against fifth-generation fighters.
-還是有機會
-F-18戰機贏不了
-Yeah. We'd still have a chance.
-In an F-18.
關鍵不是在戰機…而是飛行員
It's not the plane, sir, it's the pilot.
一點也沒錯
Exactly!
執行這任務有別的方法
There's more than one way to fly this mission.
你真的沒搞懂
You really don't get it.
執行這任務就得像獨行俠那樣飛
On this mission, a man flies like Maverick here,
否則就不可能回來
or a man does not come back.
無意冒犯
No offense intended.
但你卻老是惹毛我們
Yet somehow you always manage.
我不是批評你，只是你太保守了
Look, I don't mean to criticize.
You're conservative, that's all.
中尉
Lieutenant.
我們將進行…沒有飛行員嘗試過的空戰
We're going into combat, son,
on a level no living pilot's ever seen.
就連他也沒有過
Not even him.
沒時間糾結過去的事
That's no time to be thinking about the past.
-那是啥意思？
-公雞
-What's that supposed to mean?
-Rooster.
大家都知道他老爸和獨行俠一起飛過
I can't be the only one that knows
that Maverick flew with his old man.
-夠了
-或者是獨行俠
-That's enough.
-Or that Maverick was flying
-害死他老爸…
-中尉，夠了！
-when his old man--
-Lieutenant, that's enough!
-夠了
-你這王八蛋
-That's enough.
-You son of a bitch!
嘿，別這樣！
Hey, come on!
我沒事，嘿嘿嘿
I'm cool, I'm cool. Hey, hey, hey.
夠了
That's enough.
-他不夠資格出任務
-夠了
-He's not cut out for this mission.
-That's enough!
你明明知道
You know it.
你知道我是對的
You know I'm right.
全員解散
You're all dismissed.
（冰人：“我得見你”）
（不太方便）
（冰人：“我沒在問你”）
獨行俠
Maverick.
又復發了？
It's come back?
沒人知道
No one knows.
醫生也無能為力
There's nothing else they can do.
他連說話都很痛苦
Even speaking is painful now.
莎拉，真的很抱歉
Sarah, I'm so sorry.
上將
Admiral.
我的僚機駕駛員還好嗎？
How's my wingman?
（我想談談工作）
沒事…別替我擔心
Please, don't worry about me.
我能做什麼？
What can I do for you?
好吧
All right.
公雞還在為我做的事生氣
Well, Rooster's still angry with me about what I did.
我以為他有一天能理解
I thought eventually he would understand why.
也希望他能原諒我
I hoped he'd forgive me.
（還有時間）
任務只剩下不到三禮拜
The mission is less than three weeks away.
那孩子沒準備好
The kid's not ready.
（那就教好他）
他不要我教
He doesn't want what I have to give.
冰人，拜託
Ice, please,
別要求我派別人去赴死
don't ask me to send someone else to die.
別這麼做
Please don't…
別要我派他去
Don't ask me to send him.
派我去
Send me.
（該放手了）
我不知道該如何放手
I don't know how.
我不是教官，冰人
I'm not a teacher, Ice.
我是戰機駕駛員
I'm a fighter pilot.
海軍飛行員
A naval aviator.
那不僅僅是工作職稱
It's not what I am.
而是我與生俱來的能力
It's who I am.
我該怎麼教這種事?
How do I teach that?
就算可以，也不是公雞要的
Even if I could teach it, it's not what Rooster wants.
更不是海軍要的
It's not what the navy wants.
所以上次我才會被開除
That's why they canned me the last time.
我之所以還能在海軍是因為你
The only reason I'm here is you.
如果我派他出這項任務
If I send him on this mission,
他可能就此一去不回
he might never come home.
但若不派他去
And if I don't send him,
他絕對不會原諒我
he'll never forgive me.
不管怎樣，我都將永遠失去他
Either way, I could lose him forever.
我知道
I know.
海軍…需要獨行俠
The navy needs Maverick.
那孩子需要獨行俠
The kid needs Maverick.
這是為什麼我極力為你爭取
That's why I fought for you.
這也是為什麼你仍然在這裡
That's why you're still here.
謝謝你，冰人
Thank you, Ice,
為我所做的一切
for everything.
最後一件事
One last thing.
誰是比較厲害的飛行員？
Who's the better pilot?
你或我？
You or me?
現在氣氛正好，別破壞了！
This is a nice moment. Let's not ruin it.
♪ I Don't know what you've been told ♪
♪ but time is running out no need to take it slow ♪
♪ i'm steppin' to ya toe to toe ♪
好了…
All right, all right.
♪ Keepin' dreams alive 1999 heroes ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it right now ♪
達陣！
Touchdown!
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it ♪
♪ I Don't know what you've been told ♪
♪ but time is running out so spend it like it's gold ♪
♪ i'm livin' like i'm nine zeros ♪
♪ got no regrets even when i'm broke ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it right now ♪
♪ keepin' dreams alive 1999 heroes ♪
♪ swimming in the floods dancing on the path, hero ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it ♪
長官
Sir.
-這算什麼？
-美式足球空戰
-What is this?
-This is dogfight football.
同時進攻和防守
Offense and defense at the same time.
誰領先？
Who's winning?
他們早就沒在計分了
I think they stopped keeping score a while ago.
這批特遣隊還需要訓練，上校
This detachment still has some training to complete, Captain.
-每分每秒都很重要
-是，長官
-Every available minute matters.
-Yes, sir.
那為什麼還在打球？
So why are we out here playing games?
你說要團隊合作，長官
You said to create a team, sir.
那就是你的團隊
There's your team.
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it right now ♪
♪ keepin' dreams alive 1999 heroes ♪
♪ swimming in the floods dancing on the path, hero ♪
♪ I ain't worried 'bout it ♪
我該趁艾蜜莉雅回來前走嗎？
Should I go? Before Amelia gets back?
-她要在朋友家過夜
-那就好
-She'll be at her friend's house tonight.
-Oh, good.
妳和艾蜜莉雅看起來…
You and Amelia, you seem…
比之前更親密
a lot closer than when I last saw you.
-是啊，是真的
-怎麼做到的？
-Yeah. Yeah, we are.
-How do you manage?
這個嘛…
Well,
你知道的，她一直要我給她更多的自由
you know, she always wanted more freedom
than I thought she was ready for.
不知道這一點是遺傳到誰？
Where'd she get that from, I wonder?
我猜我發現…
I guess I realized
我也必須信任她
I also had to trust her.
偶爾讓她自己犯些錯
Let her make some of her own mistakes sometimes.
這決定不容易
Not an easy choice.
你和公雞是怎麼回事？
Is that what happened with Rooster?
我拿掉他的海軍官校申請書
I pulled his papers from the Naval Academy.
浪費了他幾年時間
Took years off his career.
為什麼？
Why?
呆頭鵝死後，他母親不希望他當飛官
His mother never wanted him to fly,
not after what happened to Goose.
她死前要我答應她，所以…
She made me promise before she died, so…
公雞知道嗎？
Does Rooster know that?
他永遠會為這件事恨我
He will always resent me for what I did.
沒必要讓他也恨她
Why should he resent her too?
這決定不容易
Not an easy choice.
我試著當他失去的父親
I was trying to be the father he lost.
只是…
I just--
我希望能做得更好
I wish I would've done it better.
但是…事實是
But the truth is…
我認為他還沒準備好
I didn't think he was ready.
現在呢？
Is he ready now?
媽，我回家了！
Mom, I'm home!
我以為妳要在凱倫家過夜
I thought you were staying at Karen's tonight.
凱倫生病，我有功課要做
Karen's sick. And I've got homework to do.
-我該走了
-你該走了
-I should go.
-You should go.
-吃過飯嗎？
-還沒，要出去吃嗎？
-Have you had dinner yet?
-Not yet. You want to go out?
沒關係，我做給妳吃
No, it's okay. I'll make you something.
馬上就下去
I'll be down in a sec!
-等等，別走那兒
-什麼？
-Wait! Not that way.
-What?
我得當個好榜樣
Look, I have an example to set.
不能第一次約會就帶男人回家
I can't be bringing guys home on a first date.
這不是第一次約會
This is not our first date.
你懂我的意思
You know what I mean.
好吧
Okay.
Fine.
這是我最後一次跳出妳家窗戶
But this is the last time I go out your window.
再說吧
We'll see.
我是說真的
No. No, I mean it.
我永遠不會再離開妳
I'm never gonna leave you again.
閉嘴啦
Oh, shut up.
快走吧
Go on, get out of here.
別再傷她的心
Just don't break her heart again.
早安
Good morning.
你們的目標鈾濃縮工廠
The uranium enrichment plant that is your target
將會提早開始運作
will be operational earlier than expected.
天然鈾在十天內會送到工廠
Raw uranium will be delivered to the plant in ten days' time.
所以你們的任務也提前一星期
As a result, your mission has been moved up one week
以免那座峽谷受到輻射汙染
in order to avoid contaminating
the target valley with radiation.
長官，這裡沒人成功完成低空航道飛行
Sir, no one here has successfully flown a low-level course.
但你們仍被命令繼續下去
Nevertheless, you've been ordered to move on.
上校
Captain.
只剩一星期進行第二階段演練
We have one week left to focus on phase two.
那是這項任務最困難的階段
It's the most difficult stage of the mission.
那是俯衝突襲行動
It's a pop-up strike with a steep dive,
需要連續出現兩個奇蹟
requiring nothing less than two consecutive miracles.
兩組戰機要以並列隊形飛行
Two pairs of F-18s will fly in a welded wing formation.
團隊合作
Teamwork.
飛行的精準度是這項任務成功…
Precise coordination of these aircraft is essential
和你們存活的關鍵
to both the mission's success and your survival.
工廠坐落在兩座山脈之間
As you know, the plant rests between two mountains.
逼近時要倒栽蔥直接俯衝
On final approach, you'll invert directly into a steep dive.
這樣才能保持低空飛行
This allows you to maintain the lowest possible altitude
也是唯一的攻擊角度
and the only possible attack angle.
目標的彈著點不到三米寬
Your target is an impact point less than three meters wide.
兩人座戰機將以雷射標示靶點
The two-seat aircraft will paint
the target with a laser bull's-eye.
第一組將發射雷射引導飛彈
The first pair will breach the reactor
進入通風口炸毀反應爐
by dropping a laser-guided bomb
on an exposed ventilation hatch.
這會為第二組製造空檔
This will create an opening for the second pair.
那是第一個奇蹟
That's miracle number one.
第二組…
The second team
將做出必殺一擊
will deliver the kill shot
徹底摧毀目標
and destroy the target.
那是第二個奇蹟
That's miracle number two.
兩組都沒有命中目標…
If either team misses the target…
未命中
That's a miss.
-任務就失敗
-可惡
-Damn it!
飛離時必須垂直爬升，以免撞到山壁
Egress is a steep high-G climb out
to avoid hitting this mountain.
高速垂直爬升至少會承受8個G力
A steep climb at that speed, you're pulling at least eight G's.
至少9個G力
Nine, minimum.
F-18機身的極限應力是7.5
The stress limit of the F-18's airframe is 7.5.
那是可接受的極限
That's the accepted limit.
想活著回來就得超越極限
To survive this mission, you'll pull beyond that,
就算必須折彎機身
even if it means bending your airframe.
重力大到你們會重達900公斤
You'll be pulling so hard, you'll weigh close to 2,000 pounds,
頭蓋骨會擠壓脊椎
your skull crushing your spine,
像被一頭大象坐在胸口擠壓肺部
your lungs imploding like an elephant's sitting on your chest,
拼了命也要避免昏厥過去
fighting with everything you have
just to keep from blacking out.
這是你們最脆弱的時刻
And this is where you'll be at your most vulnerable.
這就是棺材角
This is Coffin Corner.
就算你們沒撞上山壁
Assuming you avoid crashing into this mountain,
也會爬升到敵軍雷達範圍內
同時完全失速
you'll climb straight up into enemy radar
while losing all of your airspeed.
這時候將遇到敵軍飛彈攻擊
Within seconds, you'll be fired upon by enemy SAMs.
你們都承受過G力，但這次…
You've all faced sustained G's before, but this--
將把你們和戰機逼到臨界點
this is gonna take you and your aircraft to the breaking point.
長官，有可能成功嗎？
Sir, is this even achievable?
這個問題的答案…
The answer to that question
取決於駕駛艙內的飛行員
will come down to the pilot in the box.
-回報狀況，巴布
-我們落後12秒
-Talk to me, Bob.
-We are 12 seconds late on target.
-必須加速…
-收到，試著跟上來
-We got to move! We got to move!
-Copy. Try to stay with me.
等等，那是誰？
Wait, who's that?
藍組，你們被偵測到
Blue Team, you've been spotted.
-靠，是獨行俠
-他跑來幹嘛？
-Shit, it's Maverick.
-What the hell is he doing here?
我是來攔截的敵機，你們要怎麼辦？
I'm a bandit on course to intercept.
Blue Team, what are you gonna do?
左翼20哩，10點鐘方向，700節
He's 20 miles left. Ten o'clock. 700 knots closure.
妳決定，妳要怎麼做？
Your call. What do you want to do?
繼續下去，就快接近目標了
Continue. We're close. Stay on target.
-他繞到北方
-準備爬升
-He's swinging around to the north!
-Stand by for pop-up.
-準備雷射引導
-收到
-Be ready on that laser, Bob.
-Copy. I'm on it.
藍組，敵機逼近中
Blue Team, bandit is still closing.
爬升
Popping now.
回報狀況，巴布，獨行俠呢？
Talk to me, Bob. Where's Maverick?
他在五哩外，快速逼近
He's five miles out. He's coming fast.
-看到目標
-雷射呢？
-Target's in sight.
-Where's my laser, Bob?
無法瞄準…抱歉，無法鎖定目標
Deadeye! Deadeye! It's no good. Sorry, I can't get a lock.
來不及了，我要盲投炸彈
We're out of time. I'm dropping blind.
該死，沒命中
Damn it, missed!
-鎖定你了
-獨行俠的飛彈鎖定我們
-That's tone.
-Maverick's got missile lock on us.
靠，我們掛了
Shit! We're dead.
藍組，任務失敗，停止爬升
Blue Team, that's a fail. Level out, Coyote.
郊狼？收到嗎？
Coyote? Do you copy?
郊狼，回答
Coyote, come in.
郊狼，拉直
Coyote, level wings.
天啊，他進入G力昏迷
Oh, God. He's in G-LOC.
郊狼？郊狼？
Coyote? Coyote?
-他會墜機
-我去追他
-He's gonna burn in!
-I'm going after him.
快啊，快點鎖定…
Come on. Give me tone, give me tone, give me tone.
快醒醒，郊狼，快啊…
Snap out of it, Coyote. Come on! Come on!
加油，郊狼，快啊，快啊！
Come on, Coyote, come on. Come on!
-該死，郊狼…
-爬升
-Damn it! Coyote!
-Pull up!
-郊狼…
-爬升…
-Coyote! Coyote!
-Pull up! Pull up!
郊狼，沒事吧？
Coyote, you okay?
我沒事
I'm okay. I'm good.
那就好，今天演練夠了
Good. Good. That's enough for today.
好險喔
That was close.
太危險了
Too close.
鳥擊！
Bird strike! Bird strike!
Bird strike!
-鳳凰，左引擎起火
-爬升
-Phoenix, left engine's on fire!
-Climbing.
減速，關閉左引擎燃油
Throttling back. Shutting off fuel to left engine.
滅火
Extinguishing fire.
右引擎故障
Right engine is out!
渦輪還在旋轉，試圖重新啟動
It's still spinning. Trying to restart it.
-鳳凰，起火了，別啟動
-加速
-Phoenix, it's on fire. Don't start it.
-Throttling up.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
-起火了…
-該死
-We're on fire! We're on fire!
-Damn it!
-右引擎起火
-熄滅右引擎
-Engine fire. Right.
-Extinguishing right engine.
鳳凰、巴布，快彈跳，快彈跳！
Phoenix, Bob, punch out, punch out!
警示燈都亮著，液壓系統失靈
Warning lights everywhere! Hydraulic failure!
-操縱失效
-我無法控制了
-Flight controls.
-I can't control it.
我們要墜機了，鳳凰
我們要墜入山谷了…
We're going down, Phoenix! We're going in! We're going in!
沒救了，快彈跳…
You can't save it. Eject, eject!
彈跳…彈跳…
Eject, eject, eject!
高度，高度
Altitude. Altitude.
鳳凰和巴布要在醫院過夜接受觀察
They'll keep Phoenix and Bob
in the hospital overnight for observation.
他們不會有事
They're gonna be okay.
那就好
That's good.
我從未失去過僚機
I've never lost a wingman.
你很幸運
You're lucky.
飛得夠久，就會發生
Fly long enough, it'll happen.
會有其他人
There will be others.
你說得倒容易，沒有老婆
Easy for you to say. No wife.
沒有小孩
No kids.
掛了也不會有人悼念你
Nobody to mourn you when you burn in.
回家吧
Go home.
好好睡個覺吧
Just get some sleep.
你為什麼拿掉我官校的申請書？
Why'd you pull my papers at the Academy?
為什麼擋我的路？
Why did you stand in my way?
你當時還沒準備好
You weren't ready.
準備好什麼？
Ready for what?
-像你那樣亂飛？
-不
-Ready to fly like you?
-No.
準備忘記書本裡的規則
Ready to forget the book.
相信直覺，別猶豫，放手去做
Trust your instincts. Don't think, just do.
只要猶豫就會死，相信我
You think up there, you're dead. Believe me.
我爸相信你
My dad believed in you.
但我不會犯同樣的錯
I'm not gonna make the same mistake.
獨行俠
Maverick.
預備、瞄準、射擊
Ready, aim, fire.
預備
Ready,
瞄準
aim,
射擊
fire.
Ready,
aim,
fire.
我無法體會你現在的感受
I can only imagine what you must be feeling right now.
想休息幾天就休息幾天
Take some time. Whatever you need.
謝謝你，長官，但是任務…
I appreciate that, sir, but there is no time. The mission--
我會接手訓練他們
I'll be taking over the training from here.
長官？
Sir?
我們都知道你不想要這工作
We both know you didn't want this job, Captain.
-他們還沒準備好
-那是你的工作
-Sir, they're not ready.
-It was your job to get them ready.
他們必須相信能達成這項任務
Sir, they have to believe that this mission can be flown.
你卻只讓他們認為任務會失敗
And all you've managed to do is teach them that it can't.
-長官…
-你被禁飛了
-Sir--
-You're grounded, Captain.
永遠禁飛
Permanently.
-長官…
-就這樣
-Sir--
-That is all.
我聽說了
I heard.
很遺憾
I'm sorry.
你有什麼打算？
What are you gonna do?
冰人走了
Ice is gone.
我還能有什麼選擇？
What choice do I have?
你會找到繼續飛的方法
You'll have to find a way back on your own.
不，潘妮
No, Penny.
我已出局
I'm out.
軍旅生涯結束了
This is over.
彼得…
Pete.
就算失去你的僚機
If you lost your wingman up there,
還是會繼續奮戰
you'd keep fighting.
不會放棄
You wouldn't just give up.
他們是你的飛行員
Those are your pilots.
要是他們出事…
If anything happens to them,
你會永遠無法原諒自己
you'll never forgive yourself.
我不知道該怎麼做
I don't know what to do.
你會找到方法的
But you'll find a way.
你一定會的
I know you will.
米契爾上校不再是你們的教官
Captain Mitchell is no longer your instructor.
從今天起有新的任務參數
And as of today, there are new mission parameters.
抵達目標時間是四分鐘
Time to target is now four minutes.
你們將減速平飛進入峽谷
You'll be entering the valley level at reduced speed.
不准超過420節
Not to exceed 420 knots.
敵機不就有時間進行攔截？
Sir, won't we be giving their planes time to intercept?
對上敵機至少還有機會存活
Well, Lieutenant, you have
a fighting chance against enemy aircraft.
撞上山壁存活的機率是多少？
What are the odds of surviving
a head-on collision with a mountain?
你們要沿著北邊山壁
You'll be attacking the target from a higher altitude,
從更高的高度攻擊目標
level with the north wall.
這會更難以雷射標示目標
Gonna be a little harder to keep your lase on target,
但能避免高G力爬升
but you will avoid the high-G climb out.
敵方飛彈會擊落我們
We'll be sitting ducks for enemy missiles.
那是誰？
Who the hell is that?
獨行俠呼叫控制中心，進入A點
Maverick to Range Control. Entering Point Alpha.
請確認安全
Confirm green range.
這是控制中心…
Maverick, Range Control,
確認安全
green range is confirmed.
我沒看到你的演練行程
I don't see an event scheduled for you, sir.
我還是要去
Well, I'm going anyway.
水啦
Nice.
設定目標時間：2分15秒
Setting time to target: Two minutes 15 seconds.
2分15秒？不可能
2:15? That's impossible.
獨行俠飛往最終攻擊點
Final attack point. Maverick's inbound.
倒數三、二、一，爬升
Popping in three, two, one.
投擲炸彈
Bombs away.
正中目標！哇靠！
Bull's-eye! Holy shit!
厲害
Yes.
帥
Damn.
你讓我左右為難，上校
You have put me in a difficult position, Captain.
你一方面示範了任務的可行性
On the one hand, you have demonstrated
that this mission can be flown.
也許是唯一存活的方法
Perhaps the only way it can be survived.
另一方面…
On the other hand,
你偷開走一架數百萬美金的戰機
you did it by stealing a multimillion-dollar military aircraft
把它操到可能永遠無法再飛行
and flying it in such a manner
that it may never be airworthy again.
冰人不能再保護你了
Iceman is no longer here to protect you.
我大可以把你送去軍事法庭
I have everything I need to have you court-martialed
讓你不榮譽退伍
and dishonorably discharged.
我該怎麼做？
So what do I do?
冒著飛行員陣亡和任務失敗的風險
Risk the lives of my pilots
and perhaps the success of this mission
或是
or…
拿我的軍旅生涯賭一把
risk my career
任命你為任務隊長？
by appointing you team leader?
長官…
Sir--
中將只是問問而已，上校
I think the admiral's asking a rhetorical question, Captain.
該怎麼辦? 呆頭鵝
Talk to me, Goose.
米契爾上校
Captain Mitchell!
你屬於這裡
You're where you belong.
讓我們以你為榮
Make us proud.
很榮幸能與你們飛行
It has been an honor flying with you.
每一位都是菁英中的菁英
Each one of you represents the best of the best.
這項任務非常艱鉅
This is a very specific mission.
我的選擇完全是針對任務
My choice is a reflection of that and nothing more.
挑選兩組F小隊隊員
Choose your two Foxtrot teams.
復仇者和粉弟
Payback and Fanboy.
鳳凰和巴布
Phoenix and Bob.
你的僚機駕駛員
And your wingman.
公雞
Rooster.
其他人在航母待命
The rest of you will stand by on the carrier
隨時準備支援
for any reserve role that's required.
解散
Dismissed.
你們的目標是迫切的威脅
Your target is a clear and present threat.
受到敵國掌控的秘密鈾濃縮工廠
A secret uranium enrichment site under rogue state control.
位於地下碉堡
It's an underground bunker,
坐落在這兩座山脈之間
tucked between these two mountains.
進攻航道受到多個防空砲台防衛
Your route of ingress is heavily defended
by surface-to-air missiles
另有第五代戰機支援
backed up by fifth-generation fighters.
F-18攻擊小隊一旦跨越邊界
Once your F-18 strike team crosses the border,
雷伊泰號航空母艦
Tomahawk missiles from the USS Leyte Gulf
就會同步發射戰斧飛彈攻擊這座機場
will launch a synchronized strike on the enemy's airfield here.
炸毀那裡的跑道
This will knock out their runway.
但你們還得對付已經升空的戰機
But you'll have to contend with any planes already in the air.
戰斧飛彈擊中後，敵方就知道你們來了
The moment those Tomahawks hit,
the enemy will know you're coming.
抵達目標時間是2分30秒
Your time to target will be two minutes and 30 seconds.
超過時間就會遭到
Any longer than that, and you will be exposed
沒被擊中的戰機攻擊
to any aircraft the Tomahawks may have missed.
這是你們受訓的目的
This is what you've all been training for.
安全回來
Come home safely.
讓他們好看
You give 'em hell!
長官
Sir.
長官？
Sir?
我…
I…
我只想說…
I just want to say--
等安全回來…
We'll talk
我們再聊
when we get back.
嘿，布雷德利！布雷德利
Hey, Bradley! Bradley!
嘿
Hey.
你行的
You got this.
獨行俠
Maverick.
獨行俠？
Maverick?
你在吧？
Hey, you with me?
我不喜歡那副表情
I don't like that look, Mav.
我只有這一號表情
It's the only one I got.
謝謝你
Thank you.
要是我不能再見到你，宏多…
If I don't see you again, Hondo,
謝謝你
thank you.
這是我的榮幸，上校
It's been an honor, Captain.
匕首一號，準備彈射
Dagger One, up and ready on Catapult One.
匕首候補，待命中
Dagger Spare standing by.
匕首四號，準備好了
Dagger Four, up and ready.
匕首三號，準備好了
Dagger Three, up and ready.
匕首二號，準備好了
Dagger Two, up and ready.
支援軍機起飛，攻擊小隊準備好了
Support assets airborne. Strike package ready.
等待起飛指令
Standing by for launch decision.
出發
Send them.
匕首二號，起飛
Dagger Two away.
匕首三號，起飛
Dagger Three away.
匕首四號，起飛
Dagger Four away.
偵察機，匕首一號報到
Comanche, Dagger One. Standby check in.
偵察機就定位
Comanche 11, set.
空域安全，建議匕首小隊繼續任務
Picture clean. Recommend Dagger continue.
收到，匕首小隊低空飛行
Copy. Daggers descending below radar.
匕首小隊低於雷達，切換至鷹眼影像
Daggers now below radar. Switching to E-2 picture.
前方是敵方領地
Here we go. Enemy territory up ahead.
60秒後登陸，控制中心，回報狀況
Feet dry in 60 seconds. Comanche, Dagger One. Picture.
前方安全，你的決定
Comanche. Picture clean. Decision is yours.
收到
Copy.
展開攻擊
Dagger attack.
戰斧飛彈已經發射
Tomahawks airborne.
沒有回頭路了
No turning back now.
匕首小隊，組成進攻隊形
Daggers, assume attack formation.
組隊飛向目標
Daggers set. Proceeding to target.
2分30秒，三、二、一…計時開始
Two minutes and 30 seconds in three, two, one, mark.
-二號計時開始
-三號計時開始
-Two mark.
-Three mark.
四號計時開始
Four mark.
進入峽谷
Going in.
飛過第一個砲台
First SAM site overhead.
我們沒被雷達偵測到
Looks like we're clear on radar, Mav.
別掉以輕心
Let's not take it for granted.
更多砲台，三點鐘方向
More SAMs! Three o'clock high!
-兩分鐘後抵達目標
-收到
-We got two minutes to target.
-Copy.
我們落後幾秒，公雞，得快點
We're a few seconds behind, Rooster. We got to move.
戰斧飛彈30秒後擊中跑道
Thirty seconds to Tomahawk impact on enemy airstrip.
匕首小隊
Dagger, Comanche.
我們偵測到兩架敵機
We're picking up two bandits. Single group, two contacts.
-它們從哪來的？
-長程巡邏？
-Where the hell'd they come from?
-Long-range patrol?
它們的航向是什麼？
Comanche, what's their heading?
航向090，目標西南50哩
Bull's-eye 090, 50, tacked southwest.
它們沒看到我們，飛走了
They're headed away from us. They don't know we're here.
戰斧飛彈一擊中空軍基地
The second those Tomahawks hit the air base,
敵機就會折返防衛目標
those bandits are gonna move to defend the target.
我們得搶先一步，加速
We have to get there before they do. Increase speed.
我們會跟上，別等我
We got you, Mav. Don't wait for me.
匕首二號和四號進度落後
Sir, Daggers Two and Four are behind schedule.
抵達目標時間，1分20秒
Time to target, one minute 20.
戰斧飛彈將於三、二…
Tomahawk impact in three, two…
擊中目標，機場跑道全毀
Impact. Enemy runway is destroyed.
他們知道我們來了
They know we're coming now.
敵機轉向前去保護目標
Bandits are switching course to defend the target.
公雞，你在哪裡？
Rooster, where are you?
快點，敵機來襲
Come on, Rooster. Bandits inbound.
我們得趕上，快加速
We got to make up time now. Let's turn and burn.
小心，鳳凰
Heads up, Phoenix.
敵機距離目標兩分鐘，匕首小隊一分鐘
Sir, bandits are two minutes from target.
Daggers are one minute from target.
快啊，公雞，不快點就會死
Come on, Rooster. Move it or lose it.
我們落後了，真的得加速
Guys, we're falling behind. We really got to move.
現在不加速
If we don't increase our speed right now,
敵機就會在目標那裡等著我們
those bandits are gonna be waiting for us
when we reach the target.
爸，該怎麼做？
Talk to me, Dad.
加油，你行的，別猶豫
Come on, kid, you can do it.
放手去做
Don't think, just do.
天啊，別那麼快
Jesus, Rooster, not that fast!
這就對了，咱們上吧
That's it, kid, that's it. All right, let's go.
該死，公雞，慢一點
Damn, Rooster, take it easy.
匕首二號趕上來了
Sir, Dagger Two is reengaging.
很好，擊中目標就回來
All right, now hit your target and come home.
30秒後抵達目標，巴布，檢查雷射
Thirty seconds to target. Bob, check your laser.
檢查完畢，確認雷射辨識碼1688
Air-to-ground check complete. Laser code verified, 1688.
雷射待命中
Laser is a go!
小心
Watch your heads.
哇靠
Holy shit!
-復仇者，跟上了嗎？
-在你後方
-Payback, you with me?
-Right behind you.
鳳凰，準備攻擊
Phoenix, stand by for pop-up strike.
匕首三號就位
Dagger Three in position.
倒數三、二、一，爬升
Popping in three, two, one.
-標示目標，巴布
-匕首三號
-Get me eyes on that target, Bob.
-Dagger Three.
待命
Stand by, Mav.
-快啊，巴布
-待命
-Come on, Bob, come on.
-Stand by.
-標示目標了
-鎖定目標，投擲炸彈
-I've got it. Captured!
-Target acquired. Bombs away.
擊中了，確認命中目標
We've got impact! Check, direct hit! Direct hit!
那是第一個奇蹟
That's miracle number one.
匕首二號，回報
Dagger Two, status.
就快到了，獨行俠，就快到了
Almost there, Mav. Almost there.
粉弟，雷射咧？
Fanboy, where's my laser?
雷射出了狀況
Rooster, there's something wrong with this laser.
靠，雷射失靈…
Shit! Deadeye, deadeye, deadeye!
快點，沒時間了，快點搞定
Come on, guys, we're running out of time. Get it online!
-我正在試
-快點，粉弟
-I'm trying!
-Come on, Fanboy!
就快好了，快好了！
Nearly there! Nearly there!
-快啊
-來不及了，我要隨意投擲
-Come on, Fanboy, get it online.
-There's no time. I'm dropping blind.
-公雞，我行的
-來不及了，快走
-Rooster, I got this!
-No time. Pull up.
-等等
-投擲炸彈！投擲炸彈
-Wait!
-Bombs away! Bombs away!
正中目標！
Bull's-eye, bull's-eye, bull's-eye!
第二個奇蹟
Miracle number two.
他們飛到棺材角
Now they're in Coffin Corner.
還沒脫險
We're not out of this yet.
大家小心
Here it comes.
飛彈來襲，鳳凰，向右急轉
Radar warning! Smoke in the air. Phoenix, break right.
匕首三號發射誘彈
Emergency jettison. Dagger Three defending.
又來一枚飛彈
Here comes another one!
匕首一號發射誘彈
Dagger One defending.
公雞，回報
Rooster, status.
天啊
Oh, my God.
飛彈來襲
Smoke in the air!
-向右急轉
-Break right, Payback!
-Breaking right.
天啊，又來了
Oh, my God, here they come!
公雞，飛彈在你正後方
SAM on your six, Rooster!
發射反制火焰彈
Deploying countermeasures.
我沒被擊中
Negative contact.
匕首一號進行迴避
Dagger One defending.
-回報狀況，巴布
-鳳凰、獨行俠，向右急轉
-Talk to me, Bob.
-Break right, Phoenix! Break right! Mav!
九點鐘方向！九點鐘方向
Nine o'clock! Nine o'clock!
公雞，兩枚在你正後方
Rooster, two more on your six.
匕首二號發射誘彈
Dagger Two, defending.
-復仇者，正前方
-發射誘彈
-Payback, SAM on your nose.
-Dagger Four defending.
-七點鐘方向
-回報狀況，巴布
-Rooster, tally, seven o'clock!
-Talk to me, Bob!
-正後方
-匕首二號發射誘彈
-On our six!
-Dagger Two defending.
-向右急轉
-我看到了
-Phoenix, break right!
-I see it!
匕首二號發射誘彈
Dagger Two defending.
靠，我沒誘彈了
Shit, I'm out of flares!
公雞，迴避
Rooster, evade, evade!
甩不掉它們！它們鎖定我了
它們鎖定我了
I can't shake 'em! They're on me! They're on me!
獨行俠，不！
Mav! No!
匕首一號中彈，重複，匕首一號中彈
Dagger One is hit! I repeat, Dagger One is hit!
獨行俠被擊落
Maverick is down.
匕首一號，回報
Dagger One, status.
回報！
Status!
有誰看到他？
Anyone see him? Does anyone see him?
-匕首一號，回報
-沒看到降落傘
-Dagger One, come in!
-I didn't see a parachute.
我們得繞回去
We have to circle back.
敵機來襲，準備攻擊
Comanche. Bandits inbound. Single group, hot.
建議匕首小隊往南飛
Recommend Dagger flow south.
一分鐘後攔截
One minute to intercept.
快叫他們飛返航母
Get 'em back to the carrier now.
敵機來襲，匕首小隊飛返基地
All Daggers flow to ECP. You have bandits headed for you.
獨行俠呢？
What about Maverick?
跟他說他也無能為力，F-18打不過敵機
Tell him there's nothing he can do
for Maverick, not in a goddamn F-18.
匕首後備要求進行空中支援
Dagger Spare request permission to launch and fly air cover.
不准
Negative, Spare.
-展開搜救行動
-不行，空中有敵機
-Launch search and rescue.
-Negative. Not with bandits in the air.
-獨行俠還活著
-今天不能再損失任何人
-But, sir, Maverick is still out there.
-We are not losing anyone else today.
命令他們回來
Get 'em home now.
匕首小隊，不准救援
Dagger, you are not to engage.
重複，不准救援
Repeat, do not engage.
匕首二號飛返航母，確認
Dagger Two, return to carrier. Acknowledge.
確認
Acknowledge.
公雞，敵機逼近，不能回去
Rooster, those bandits are closing. We can't go back.
公雞，他死了
Rooster, he's gone.
獨行俠死了
Maverick's gone.
噢，不…
Oh, no, no.
匕首二號被擊中
Dagger Two is hit.
匕首二號，回報
Dagger Two, come in.
匕首二號，收到嗎？
Dagger Two, do you copy?
匕首二號，回報
Dagger Two, come in.
你沒事吧？
You all right?
我沒事，你呢？
Yeah, I'm good. You all right?
搞什麼鬼？
What the hell?
-你來幹嘛？
-我來幹嘛？
-What are you doing here?
-What am I doing here?
我替你擋飛彈不是讓你也落難
You think I took that missile
so you could be down here with me?
你早就該飛返航母了
You should be back on the carrier by now!
我救了你一命
I saved your life!
我救了你，那才是重點
I saved your life. That's the whole point.
你到底在想什麼？
What the hell were you even thinking?
你叫我不要想
You told me not to think!
這樣嘛…
Well,
見到你真好
it's good to see you.
我也是
It's good to see you too.
有什麼計畫？
So what's the plan?
不是吧
You're not serious.
你在開玩笑吧
You've got to be shitting me.
F-14戰機？
An F-14?
我開那玩意擊落三架米格機
I shot down three MiGs in one of those.
那古董能不能飛都不知道
We don't even know if that bag of ass can fly.
-試試就知道
-獨行俠
-Let's find out.
-Mav!
好吧
Okay.
-前面有人
-是啊
-There's guys up there, Mav.
-Yeah.
-那裡有更多人
-好吧
-There's more over there.
-Okay.
-開始跑吧
-好啊，跑，跑啊
-Let's start running.
-Yeah, run. Run.
我會打信號要你充氣
Once I give you the signal for air,
打開這開關直到針頭指到120
you're gonna flip this switch until the needle gets to 120.
引擎啟動後
When the engine starts,
馬上拔除一切
you got to pull out the pins and disconnect everything.
-你瞭嗎？
-我瞭
-You understand?
-Yeah.
好耶！
Yes!
我一上去就收起梯子
Once I'm up, stow the ladder.
好吧，哇塞
Okay. Wow.
很久沒開了
It's been a minute, huh, Mav?
天啊，這玩意超老舊的
Oh, my God. This thing is so old.
好吧
All right.
-關閉座艙罩
-好
-Canopy?
-Clear.
兩條跑道都被炸毀
Both runways are cratered.
該怎麼讓這老古董起飛？
How we gonna get this museum piece in the air?
你為什麼延展機翼？
Why are the wings coming out, Mav?
這是滑行道，不是跑道
Mav, this is a taxiway, not a runway.
而且是很短的滑行道
This is a very short taxiway, Mav.
坐好了
Just hang on.
哇咧！
Holy shit!
快點，快點
Come on, come on, come on.
指針能運作
Needle's alive.
-獨行俠？
-很好，快點…
-Mav?
-That's it. Come on, come on!
好吧
All right.
-獨行俠
-起飛囉
-Mav!
-Here we go.
天啊
Holy shit.
長官，收到公雞的信號
Sir, we're receiving a signal from Rooster's ESAT.
看起來是故障
But there seems to be a malfunction.
-信號又消失了？
-不是
-Have you lost him?
-No, sir.
他進入超音速
He's supersonic.
他在飛行
He's airborne.
-用什麼飛？
-長官
-In what?
-Sir.
偵察機回報一架F-14戰機正在飛來
Overwatch reports an F-14 Tomcat is
airborne and on course for our position.
不可能，不可能
Can't be. It can't be!
是獨行俠
Maverick.
公雞，快聯絡航母
Okay, Rooster, get us in touch with the boat.
我正在試
I'm working on it.
無線電失效，沒有雷達，一切都故障
Radio's out. No radar. Everything's dead back here.
-教我怎麼做
-先是無線電
-What do I do? Talk me through it.
-Okay, first the radio.
打開…
Throw the…
UHF-2斷路器
the UHF-2 circuit breaker.
試試看
Try that.
有一大堆斷路器，哪一個？
There's 300 breakers back here. Anything more specific?
不知道，那是你爸的領域
I don't know. That was your dad's department.
我會想辦法
I'll figure it out.
兩架敵機在底下五點鐘方向
Mav, tally two, 5:00 low.
該怎麼辦？
What do we do?
聽好，冷靜點
Okay, listen. Just be cool.
我們若是暴露了身分早就死了
If they knew who we were, we'd be dead already.
他們來了
Well, here they come.
-有啥打算？
-戴上面罩
-What's your plan?
-Just put your mask on.
記住，我們是同一國的
Remember, we're on the same team.
揮手和微笑
Just wave and smile.
那什麼信號？他在說啥？
What's that signal? What's he saying?
我不知道他在說什麼
No idea. I have no idea what he's saying.
-這個咧？
-我也沒看過
-What about that one? Any idea?
-No, never seen that one either.
靠，他的僚機進入攻擊位置
Oh, shit. His wingman is moving into weapons envelope.
聽好了
All right, listen up.
我一下令你就抓住頭上的圓環
When I tell you, you grab those rings above your head.
那是彈跳把手
That's the ejection handle.
不能逃離他們嗎？
Mav, can we outrun these guys?
他們有飛彈和機關槍
Not their missiles and guns.
那就要空戰囉
Then it's a dogfight.
一架F-14…對上第五代戰機？
An F-14 against fifth-gen fighters?
關鍵不在飛機，而是飛行員
It's not the plane, it's the pilot.
我不在你肯定會迎敵
You'd go after 'em if I wasn't here.
但你在啊
But you are here.
拜託，獨行俠
Come on, Mav.
別猶豫
Don't think.
放手去做
Just do.
看到飛彈就告訴我
Tell me when you see smoke in the air.
-飛彈來襲！飛彈來襲
-坐好了
-Smoke in the air! Smoke in the air!
-Hang on.
好耶，擊落了一架！擊落了一架
Yeah, Mav! Splash one! Splash one!
又來一枚飛彈
Here comes another one.
公雞，發射誘彈
Rooster, flares! Now, now, now!
分配氣閥
Splitting the throttles.
繞回去
Coming around.
-快鎖定，快鎖定
-鎖定了
-Give me tone, give me tone.
-You got him, Mav! You got him!
發射飛彈
Taking the shot.
搞什麼？
What the--
哇咧，那是怎樣？
Holy shit! What the fuck was that?
坐好了，我要低飛
Hang on. We got to get low.
峽谷會干擾他的瞄準器
The terrain will confuse his targeting system.
他來了
Here he comes!
回報狀況，他在哪裡？
Talk to me, Rooster. Where is he?
他緊追不捨
He's still on us!
-我們被擊中，被擊中
-可惡
-We took a hit! We took a hit!
-Damn it!
-快秀一些你的招術
-坐好了
-Come on, Mav. Do some of that pilot shit.
-Brace yourself.
哇咧
Holy shit.
鎖定他，發射飛彈
I got tone. Taking the shot.
可惡
Damn it!
沒飛彈了，改用機關槍
Out of missiles. Switching to guns.
快啊，快啊
Come on, Mav, come on.
-擊中了，獨行俠
-還沒結束
-You got him, Mav!
-It's not over yet.
-最後的機會
-你行的
-One last chance.
-You can do this.
加油
Come on, Maverick.
好耶，擊落第二架
Yes! Splash two!
-我修好無線電
-好樣的
-Mav, I got the radio on.
-Outstanding.
-呼叫航母
-收到
-Get us in touch with the boat.
-Copy that.
天啊
Oh, my God.
這傢伙在哪裡？
Where the hell is this guy?
他在正前方
He's on our nose.
彈藥用完了
Damn it, we're out of ammo.
飛彈來襲，公雞，發射誘彈
Smoke in the air! Rooster, flares!
好險啊
That was close.
沒有誘彈了
We're out of flares, Mav.
靠，他已經追上來了
Shit, he's already on us.
情況不妙
This is not good.
-我們又被擊中
-不不不
-We took another hit!
-No, no, no!
不能再被擊中了
We can't take much more of this.
逃不了，只能彈跳
We can't outrun this guy. We got to eject.
-什麼？
-必須爬升
-What?
-We need altitude.
我下令就拉下彈跳把手
Pull the ejection handles the second I tell you.
-等等
-沒別的辦法
-Mav, wait!
-Rooster, there's no other way.
彈跳…彈跳…
Eject, eject, eject!
快拉把手，彈跳
Rooster, pull the handle! Eject!
把手拉不動
It's not working.
獨行俠！
Mav!
對不起
I'm sorry.
對不起，呆頭鵝
I'm sorry, Goose.
午安，兩位，這是你們的救星
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.
This is your savior speaking.
請繫好安全帶
Please fasten your seat belts,
收好桌子，豎直椅背
return your tray tables to their locked and upright positions
準備降落
and prepare for landing.
劊子手，你看起來不賴
Hey, Hangman, you look good.
我很厲害，公雞，非常厲害
I am good, Rooster. I'm very good.
航母上見
I'll see you back on deck.
我順風飛行
Maverick is downwind.
沒有起落架或尾鉤
收起阻攔索，架起護網
No front landing gear. No tailhook.
Pull the cable and raise the barricade.
緊急迫降，架起護網！
Foul deck! Raise the barricade!
Go!
別告訴我引擎失效了
Please don't tell me we lost an engine.
-好，那我就不說
-好吧
-All right, I won't tell you that.
-Okay.
還好吧？
You good?
我很好
Yeah. I'm good.
-你又擊落一架敵機
-兩架了
-Chalked yourself another kill.
-That makes two.
獨行俠擊落五架，他才是王牌
Mav has five. Makes him an ace.
米契爾上校…
Captain Mitchell! Captain Mitchell!
長官
Sir.
謝謝你救我一命
Thank you for saving my life.
我爸也會這麼做
It's what my dad would've done.
嘿，獨行俠
Hey, Mav.
吉米
Jimmy.
那个…
Is…
潘妮在嗎？
Is Penny around?
她帶艾蜜莉雅去航船
She took Amelia on a sailing trip.
有說幾時回來嗎？
Did she say when she'd be back?
她沒說喔
You know, she didn't.
你要喝什麼嗎？
Can I get you anything?
Get in there.
♪ Hold my hand ♪
♪ everything will be okay ♪
♪ I heard from the heavens that clouds have been gray ♪
♪ hold me close ♪
♪ wrap me in your aching arms ♪
♪ I see that you're hurtin' ♪
♪ why'd you take so long ♪
♪ to tell me you need me? ♪
♪ I see that you're bleeding ♪
♪ you Don't need to show me again ♪
♪ but if you decide to ♪
♪ i'll ride in this life with you ♪
♪ I won't let go till the end ♪
♪ so cry tonight ♪
♪ but Don't you let go of my hand ♪
♪ you can cry every last tear ♪
♪ I won't leave till I understand ♪
♪ promise me
just hold my hand ♪
♪ Hold my hand, hold my ♪
♪ hold my hand, hold my hand ♪
♪ i'll be right here
hold my hand ♪
♪ hold my hand, hold my ♪
♪ hold my hand, hold my hand ♪
♪ i'll be right here
hold my hand ♪
♪ hold my hand ♪
♪ my hand ♪
♪ hold my hand, hold my hand ♪
♪ Revvin' up your engine listen to her howlin' roar ♪
（謹獻給東尼史考特）
字幕翻譯：黃文俊
双语校对：秦仁